A new breed of rock star
Rock Dog is a animation, adventure, comedy film directed by Ash Brannon.
When a radio falls from the sky into the hands of a wide-eyed Tibetan Mastiff, he leaves home to fulfill his
dream of becoming a musician, setting into motion a series of completely unexpected events.
Bodi (voice), played by Luke Wilson.
Angus Scattergood (voice), played by Eddie Izzard.
Khampa (voice), played by J.K. Simmons.
Linnux (voice), played by Lewis Black.
Riff (voice), played by Kenan Thompson.
Darma (voice), played by Mae Whitman.
Rock Dog (simplified Chinese: 摇滚藏獒; traditional Chinese: 搖滾藏獒; pinyin: Yáogǔn Zàng'áo, literally Rock and Roll Tibetan Mastiff) is a 2016 animated comedy film
directed by Ash Brannon and written by Brannon and Kurt Voelker.The film is loosely based on the Chinese graphic novel Tibetan Rock Dog by Zheng Jun.
It features the voices of Eddie Izzard, J.
Simmons, Lewis Black, Luke Wilson, Kenan Thompson, Mae
Whitman, Jorge Garcia, Matt Dillon, and Sam Elliott.
The film focuses on a young Tibetan Mastiff who leaves his mountain home village to
become a rock musician in the big city after a radio falls from the sky.
Rock Dog was released on July 8, 2016, in China by Huayi Brothers and on
February 24, 2017, in the United States, by Lionsgate.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and underperformed at the box
office, grossing $24 million against a $60 million budget.
It was followed by two direct-to-video sequels,  Rock Dog 2: Rock Around
the Park in 2021 and Rock Dog 3: Battle the Beat in 2023.
The film explores themes of naivety, rock 'n' roll, guitar, musician, village.
The tone is lighthearted.